(アスマ)あんときは
やっぱ 若かったなぁ…。
I sure was young...
back then...
((三代目 : 大名の護衛
ご苦労だったな。
Good work...
on the Feudal Lord escort.
何が不満なんだ！
What's your beef?!
アンタの言ったとおり オレは玉を…➡
I protected the king, the Feudal Lord
just as you told me to do!
大名を守ったんだ。
なぜ オレを認めようとしない!?
Why don't you even attempt
to acknowledge me?!
(三代目)玉か…。
King... huh...?
(アスマ)少しは オレのことを
認めたらどうなんだ！ 親父！
How about acknowledging me
at least a little bit, Dad?!
You don't understand...
お前は わかっておらん。
玉を守るための戦いが
どれほど難しく➡
how difficult and important a battle
to protect the king is.
大切なのかということを。
死傷者が出たのは わかっている。
I understand that people died.
だが
忍の任務に 犠牲はつきものだ。
But sacrifice comes with
a Shinobi mission.
フンッ
今のお前には 到底わかるまいよ。
You can't possibly
understand now...
玉を守るという 本当の意味をな。
the true significance of
protecting the king.
(アンタは オレを
認めたくないだけなんだ！))
You just don't want to
acknowledge me!
(アスマ)今なら
アンタの言っていたことも➡
Now I get the feeling...
I kind of understand what
you were talking about.
少しは わかる気がするよ。
木ノ葉を離れたり➡
I'm sorry I left the Hidden Leaf...
and just did whatever I wanted.
好き勝手なことばかりして
悪かったな。
後悔はしてねえけどな…。
I have no regrets, though.
Now I feel like it wasn't so bad
being born into the Sarutobi Clan.
今は 猿飛一族に生まれたのも
悪くねえと思えるぜ。
アンタは ちゃんと
里長としての役目を果たした。
You properly fulfilled your duty
as leader of the village...
You were a cool dad...
かっこいい親父だったよ。
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
I haven't learned "sadness" yet.
kanashimi wa mada oboerarezu
And I'm just starting to grasp "misery".
setsunasa wa ima tsukami hajimeta
Even this feeling I hold towards you.
anata e to idaku kono kanjou mo
Is now turning into "words".
ima kotoba ni wakatteku
Waking up from the dream of this unknown world.
michi naru sekai no yume kara mezamete
I spread these wings and fly.
kono hane wo hiroge tobi datsu
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Knowing I'll find the answer,
tsuki nuketara
If I pierce through it.
mitsukaru to shitte
if I break free,
furikiru hodo
From that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
The Quietly Approaching Threat
(木ノ葉丸)角材運びも 任務だコレ。
Carrying lumber is a mission, too!
がんばって運ぶんだな
えっほだコレ… うわっ！
Let's do our best to carry it.
Heave ho...
Whoa!
どうしたんだ!? コレ！
Wh-What's the matter?
(ウドン)ハァ ハァ…
ちょ ちょっと休もう。
L-Let's take a little break.
We're not used to this kind of work.
(モエギ)慣れない仕事だもんねぇ。
だらしないぞ コレ！
You guys are a sorry bunch.
The village has been saved and
the Fifth Hokage was unharmed.
里は救われたし
五代目も無事だった。
でも それは ナルトにいちゃんたちの
活躍があってのことなんだな コレ。
But that was because of the great efforts
by Brother Naruto and the others...
オレたちも 里を支えられるように➡
We have to do our best with
whatever we can do,
オレたちのできることで
がんばらなきゃならないんだぞ！
so we'll also be able to
support the village!
Well said.
(イルカ)よく言ったぞ！
(イルカ)次代の木ノ葉を支えるのは
お前たちだ。
You guys are the ones who will support
the Hidden Leaf in the next generation.
今回の事件では
ナルトも大活躍したようだしな。
And it seems Naruto played a huge role
in the earlier incident.
Iruka Sensei.
イルカ先生！
立派な教え子を持って
オレは嬉しいよ。
I'm happy to
have such amazing students.
木ノ葉丸君 もう大丈夫だよ。
Konohamaru. I'm okay now.
みんなが一丸となれば➡
If we all work together,
we'll be okay no matter what happens.
どんなことが起きたって
大丈夫なんだな コレ。
(綱手)次！
Next!
- Next!
- Yes!
(綱手)次！
(シズネ)はい！
次！ 次！ 次！ 次！
Next! Next! Next!
Next!
(綱手)遅いぞ！ 次 次 次！
You're too slow! Next! Next, next!
次！ ん… どうした？
次の書類は？
Next!
What's the matter?!
Where are the next documents?!
Oh, uh... that's it...
You're finished!
あっ えっと
終わり… 終わりです。
そうか。
I see.
め… 珍しいですね。
Th-This is a first, isn't it?
綱手様が こんなに
マジメに お仕事されるなんて。
You don't usually take your work
this seriously, Tsunade-sama.
まあな。
You could say that.
((ホムラ : 聞けば
たった数名の賊に この騒ぎ。
It seems there was quite the commotion
over just a couple of thieves...
(コハル)情けないのぉ 綱手姫。
That's pathetic, Princess Tsunade.
周辺諸国
いや 大名に知れただけで➡
Just from this...
the Hidden Leaf Village will turn
into a laughingstock
木ノ葉の里は いい笑いものじゃ。
amongst the surrounding lands
and the Feudal Lord.
お前の出す指示が
後手後手に回っとるようだ。
It seems your orders
are slow in coming
決断力の にぶさは
里を危うくする。
and then become forestalled!
すべては
火影たる お前の責務じゃ。
Your slow decision-making
endangers the village.
(肝に銘じておくことじゃな))
It's all your responsibility as the Hokage.
Bear this firmly in mind!
《綱手 : 年寄りどもが
好き勝手 言いおって。
Those old geezers
and their big mouths...
このうえ 残務が滞るようなら➡
Who knows what they'll say if
unfinished work continues to stack up...
何を言われるか
わかったものではないからな》
Damn it!
クソッ！
あ… そ そうだ。
Oh, that's right.
The report from the one
自来也様への つなぎに出ていた➡
who was sent to contact
Jiraiya-sama has arrived.
あの方からの報告書が
上がってきました。
ん？ そうか 帰ってきたか。
I see. So he's back...
You got hospitalized again because
you tried to act cool and snuck out
(サクラ)まだ キズも治ってないのに➡
かっこつけて
病院 抜け出したりするから➡
even though your injury hasn't healed yet.
また入院なんてことになるのよ。
(サイ)ハハハ！
友達のピンチに駆けつけると➡
It says in this book that the bonds
of friendship grow deeper
友情の絆が深まるって この本に。
if you rush to a friend who's in a jam...
え？ それマンガでしょ？
That's manga, right?
You're so random these days.
アンタ このところ 手当たり次第ね。
はい。
Here...
ん？ 何？
What?
(サイ)好意を持ってくれた女性は➡
It seems women who like
you will feed you.
こういう場合
食べさせてくれると…。
Well, it's not like
I'm testing you or anything...
いや キミを
試したわけじゃないんだけど。
ハァ… アンタねぇ。
Look you...
Sakura-chan.
(ナルト)サクラちゃ～ん。
サクラちゃん
もう食べれねえってばよ。
S-Sakura-chan...
I-I can't eat anymore...
あ そんなにサクラちゃんが
食べてほしいって…。
Oh, but if you insist I eat, then...
し… しようがない。 あ～ん。
死ぬほど食ってろ！
んがっ！
Eat until you die!
(カカシ)よっ！ ん？
Yo! Hm?
I-I can't breathe...
サクラは ナルトには リンゴを食べさせた。
Sakura fed Naruto an apple...
ということは…。
あぁ～ もう！
Which means...
Oh, for crying out loud!
Why can't I have someone normal
on my team?!
なんで ウチの班には
ろくなヤツが いないのよ！
Huh?
え？ え？ どうしたの？
What happened?
((近隣諸国 ５か国７か所で
同一と思われる➡
Attacks by what is suspected to be
the same two-man Shinobi team
in seven locations in five
neighboring lands have been verified.
ツーマンセルの忍による戦闘を確認。
いまだ 火ノ国への侵入は
果たしていないものの➡
Although they have not yet succeeded
in invading the Land of Fire,
(その行動ラインから
時間の問題かと…))
judging from their line of action,
it's only a matter of time...
綱手様？
Tsunade-sama?
So the Akatsuki Organization
has gone into action.
《動き出したか… 暁》
(角都)やるぞ。
(飛段)ちょい待ち。
Let's do this.
Hold it.
(飛段)あれ やる前には➡
Before doing that...
I must pray to my god.
ちゃんと
神に祈りを捧げねえとな。
You're always
such a pain in the neck.
いつも いつも 面倒くさいヤツだ。
It's a pain
in the neck for me, too.
オレだって 面倒くせえけど➡
But the commandments are strict,
so I have no choice, do I?!
戒律 厳しいんだから
しようがねえだろ。
You probably think
you've got me cornered...
(ユギト)アンタら 私を
追い込んだつもりだろうが…➡
But you don't.
そうじゃない…
私が アンタらを誘い込んだのさ！
I lured you guys here, you see!
アンタらが 暁とわかった以上
逃がすわけにはいかない。
Now that I know
you are with the Akatsuki,
I cannot let you escape.
あ～あ…
ふさがれちまったぜ 角都。
Oh, man...
We're trapped, Kakuzu...
No problem.
Actually, this is favorable for us.
(角都)問題ない… むしろ好都合。
雲隠れの二位
ユギトの名にかけて… 殺す！
In the name of Ni'i Yugito
of the Hidden Clouds...
I'll kill you!
Huh...? What?
はぁ？ 何？ その 「殺す」とかさ➡
What's up with that,
"I'll kill you", stuff?
When people show me all
that enthusiasm and stuff...
なんか そういう意気込み
みたいなのぶつけられるとさ➡
I start to get irritated.
イラっとくんだよね！
And when I'm irritated,
I become enraged.
で イラっとくると
頭に血が昇る 頭に血が昇ると…。
And when I become enraged...
Shut up, Hidan.
(角都)うるさい。 黙れ 飛段。
はいはい。
Okay. okay...
But you know,
when I become enraged,
でもよ 頭に血が昇ると
もう目的なんて どうでもいいや。
I start feeling like,
"I don't care about our objective.
I just want to smash everything."
ぶっ壊しちまおう
って気になんだよ。
Knock it off, Hidan.
The objective is absolute.
いいかげんいしろ 飛段。
目的は絶対だ。
This mission doesn't go along
with my religion in the first place.
(飛段)だいたい 今回のノルマは
オレの宗派にゃ合わねえんだよ。
The motto of the Jashin religion
is mass slaughter.
ジャシン教は殺戮がモットー。
半殺しはダメだと戒律で決まってる。
Leaving people alive goes
against the commandments.
From the outset,
戒律 破るような仕事 はなから
やる気にはならねえぜ ホント。
I'm not inclined
to take part in a mission
that breaks
the commandments.
オレは
こう見えても信心深いんだぜ。
I may not look it,
but I'm quite devout!
So not being able to kill
is a pain in the neck.
というわけで
殺せねえのは 面倒くせえから➡
So how about we settle this
by talking things over?
ここは 話し合いで解決しないか？
話し合いだと？
Talking things over, you say?
《なんだ コイツ…》
What's up with this guy?
Why don't you
just come quietly?
おとなしく捕まってくんねえかな。
ふざけるな!!
Stop messing around!
Huh...? Looks like that's a no.
あれ？ ダメみたいだな。
お前は バカか！
Are you an idiot?
Come on. Are you kidding me?
おいおい マジかよ。
ガァ～！
(飛段)なんだ この人柱力…
完全に尾獣化してやがるぜ。
What's up with this Jinchuriki?
She's totally morphed into a Tailed Beast.
ガァ～！
Oh man...
あ～あ！
(飛段)やべっ！
Uh-oh!
あちぃ！
コイツ 猫舌じゃねえのかよ！
Hot!
Don't cats have sensitive tongues
for hot stuff?
So this is the Two-Tails monster cat
known as the wraith...
コイツが生霊といわれる
二尾の化け猫か…。
オレは まさしく
袋のネズミってわけだな。
And I'm a rat in a cage, no less.
ククク… 笑えねえ。
This is not amusing...
(カカシ)ほぉ～。
オレのいない間に大活躍だったのね。
Oh-ho.
So you made a great showing
while I was gone, huh?
Where the hell were you,
Kakashi-sensei?
カカシ先生こそ いったい
どこ行ってたんだってばよぉ。
まぁ ちょっとね…。
Oh... nowhere special.
アスマ先生。
ん？
Asuma-sensei.
I knew you'd be here.
やっぱ ここか…
カカシ ちょっといいか？
Kakashi, got a minute?
I want to talk to you...
話があるんだ…
ナルト サイ… ほら お見舞いだ。
Naruto, Sai...
Here, a get well gift!
Yikes!
I've had enough apples...
リンゴは もう こりごりだってばよ。
(アスマ)お前 外の様子を
見て回ってきたそうじゃないか。
I hear you checked out what
was happening outside...
You could say that...
まあね。
いい天気だ。
What a nice day.
ん？ あぁ… そうだな。
Hm? Yeah... it is.
Naruto and Sakura are
coming along very well.
ナルトもサクラも よく成長している。
(カカシ)
シカマル チョウジ いの それぞれにな…。
And so are Shikamaru,
Choji and Ino...
The next generation is
growing up quickly.
次の世代の若者が
どんどん成長してきて➡
They'll overtake us just like that...
お前やオレを
あっという間に追い抜いていく。
Come on.
I still won't be giving in to them.
(アスマ)おいおい オレは まだまだ
ヤツらには負けねえぞ。
アハハハ…。
(アスマ)しかし 木ノ葉にとっては
喜ぶべきことだな。
But this is something the Hidden Leaf
should be very pleased about.
(カカシ)で？
So...
話って何だ？
What did you want to talk about?
Hm? Oh, as it happens...
イヤ… 実はな…。
There you are...
I finally found you.
(紅)いたいた… やっと見つけた。
紅か…。 なんか用か？
Kurenai...
Did you need something?
アスマが来てるって聞いてね。
I heard Asuma was here, you see...
No kidding...?
ふ～ん…。 で アスマ 話ってのは？
So, Asuma...
What did you want to talk about?
Uh, I'll tell you later... Sorry.
いや また今度 ゆっくり話す。
悪いな…。
Now I really want to know...
すごい気になるな…。
What're you doing, Naruto?
何やってるのよ ナルト。
こんなところで
寝てる場合じゃねえってばよ。
I don't have the time to be
lying around here.
I need to get back to my training...
修業の続きをつけてもらわねえと。
That being said, you're still...
だからって… アンタ まだ…。
I'm still too weak.
オレは まだまだ弱い…。
だから… だからこそ➡
That's why...
That's exactly why...
みんなを傷つけない力を…
みんなを守る力を…。
I have to get stronger
to get power that won't hurt everyone...
Power that will protect everyone.
That's why I have to get stronger.
そのためにも
もっと強くならなくちゃなんねえ。
(サクラ)ナルト…。
(カカシ)まっ そう焦るな。
Naruto...
Well, hold your horses...
今のところは
傷を治すのが修業だ。
Right now, your training is
to heal those wounds.
カカシ先生…！
(カカシ)特に ナルト。
Kakashi-sensei!
And let me make this clear to you,
in particular, Naruto...
お前には 念を押しておく。
へ？
Huh?
退院したら 「もっと 入院
しとくんだった」ってくらい➡
If you leave the hospital,
what awaits is training so severe
you'll wish you'd stayed
in the hospital longer.
過酷な修業が待ってるから
覚悟しておくように。
So be prepared for that!
うっ… オ オッス！
わかったってばよ…。
R-Right...!
I-I understand...
Okay...
Now he won't push things too far.
《ふむ… これくらい言っておけば
ムチャはしないでしょ》
Sakura...
サクラ。
は はい。
Y-Yes...?!
I've got something to take care of.
So I leave the rest to you.
オレは これから 用があるので➡
あとのことは頼んだよ。
え…。
What...?
くれぐれも ムリさせないように。
じゃあ。
Make sure you don't let him
overdo things...
Bye!
Oh man, isn't he slick!
もう 調子いいんだから。
(綱手)報告書は読んだ。
I read the report.
Does it look like Naruto will be able
to learn a new Jutsu?
ナルトの新術 どうにかなりそうか？
How about it?
どうなのだ？
I don't know.
わかりません。
(シズネ)そんな…。
No way.
I'm not sure...
わかりませんが
アイツなら やるでしょう。
But he can probably do it...
That new training approach
is yielding results, after all.
例の修業方法も
成果をあげてますしね。
And more importantly...
何より… アイツには
明確な目標がありますからね。
He has a clear objective.
サスケか…。
Sasuke... huh?
It's already been thirty minutes.
Aren't you done yet, Hidan?
30分も経ってるぞ。
まだか？ 飛段。
Shut up!
Don't interfere with the ritual!
うるせえよ！ 儀式のジャマすんな！
Ouch...
いてっ…。
Can't you skip some of that
毎度毎度 その悪趣味な祈り
少しは省略できんのか？
perverse praying
you do each and every time?
Let's get right to the next one.
さっさと次へいくぞ。
This is a pain in the neck for me too.
オレだって
面倒くせえけど➡
But I have no choice
but to follow the commandments.
戒律なんだから
しようがねえだろ！
And what do you mean by skip?!
それに 省略って何だ 省略って！
神への冒涜だぞ！
That's blasphemy against God!
One more to go for our mission.
(角都)オレたちのノルマは あと一匹。
One by one...
(角都)しらみつぶしだな…。
次は 火ノ国だ！
Next is the Land of Fire.
Young people
iiijii na riyuu
I'll always accept your excuses
issai yurusu jakuhai
I summoned the rescue team too
resukuyuu tai mo yonde oita
So
dakara
Please kiss me please kiss me
puriizu kisu mii purizu kisu mi
All night
all night
The magic of a fallen angel or the silly pranks of a little demon
datenshi no mahou ka koakuma no chachi na itazura
Before it gets boring
tsuman naku nacchau mae ni
go and hurl
soore de houre
The bowling ball
bouringu booru
It's a strange existence
kibutsuhason zai nado
I know it already
shouchi no suke
It looks breakable...
kowaresou de
Clear the way with those sloppy emotions
tocchirakatta kanjou de kirihirake yo
It looks breakable
kowaresou de
Yet it's not our victory
kowasenai bokura no shouri
尾獣について 新たに
わかったことがあるそうだな？
(シズネ)はい ９つの尾獣のうち
すでに 暁に奪われたものは➡
Next Episode
For crying out loud.
一尾の守鶴を含めて ４匹。
(綱手)約半数か…。
That Naruto is already starting his training,
even though he's still on the mend.
(シズネ)残りは
ナルト君の九尾ほか ４匹。
Knowing who he is,
there's no doubt he'll get reckless.
それで
その尾獣についての情報は？
Getting stronger through
sheer determination
just isn't done anymore.
確定の情報ではありませんが➡
And excessive training could
also have a reverse effect.
少なくとも うち２名は
人柱力のようです。
Not only that, he also has
the physical idiosyncrasy
that allows him to work much harder
than other people.
(綱手)人柱力は 本来
国家レベルの機密情報。
The least I can do is help him
in whatever way I can.
えぇ しかし 人柱力一人の
素性がわかりました。
Akatsuki's Invasion
Next time: "Akatsuki's Invasion"
本当か？ で 所在は？
(シズネ)雷の国 雲隠れの里
二位 ユギトという者です。
I hear we've found some new information
about the tailed beasts.
雲隠れの 二位 ユギト…。
Yes.
Including the One-Tail
ご苦労。 引き続き 手を尽くし
調査を進めてくれ。
the Akatsuki have stolen four
of the nine tailed beasts...
(シズネ)はい わかりました。
About half of them, huh?
《いまだ 暁の目的は
見えないままか…》
There's Naruto's Nine-Tails
and four others.
So what about information on
the remaining four tailed beasts?
It's not solid information, but it appears
at least two of them are Jinchuriki.
Information about the Jinchuriki is
supposed to be classified at a state level.
Yes. But we found out the identity
of one of the Jinchuriki.
Really?! What of
that Jinchuriki's whereabouts?
Her name is Yugito Ni 'i and she's
from the Village Hidden in the Clouds
in the Land of Lightning.
Nii Yugito from
the Hidden Clouds...
Good work. Continue the investigation
doing everything you can.
Yes, ma'am. Understood.
So we still don't know
the objective of the Akatsuki...